realo.be 2019-06-08

# Realo - Privacy policy

The Website is owned by Realo NV, a company registered in Ghent, Belgium with company number 0543.772.595 located at Sint-Jacobsnieuwstraat 17, 9000 Ghent.

This Privacy Statement was created in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your right to privacy and data protection. Realo processes your personal data with every reasonable safeguard for your protection and in conformity with this Privacy Statement and with the strict rules of Belgian and European data protection legislation.

This Privacy Statement is a part of Realo's Terms & Conditions and should be read carefully. It specifies your rights and explains how you can exercise them. Any use of the Website implies the acceptance of the entire Privacy Statement.

## Types of personal data we collect

**Public information added by you:**

  * Information in your profile, photos...
  * Messages sent to other users or agents.
  * Your listings.
  * Information about your home.

* * *

**Private information added by you:**

  * Administrative data such as your username and password.
  * Your settings.
  * Messages, questions or job positions that you send to us (for example via the helpdesk, as an answer to a job position or via our business center)
  * Information that you provide in relationship to the usage of certain functionalities of our Website (for example when publishing a property or requesting an estimate)

* * *

**History and logs:**

  * Time, date and URL of all Realo pages visited by you.
  * The searches you perform on the website.
  * Technical information regarding your Internet browser and computer.

During your registration (and afterwards), you can provide us with information about your name, email address, gender, date of birth, location and some optional details about yourself. With the exception of gender and birthday, your Realo account details can be edited at any given moment.

All your personal data will be processed only with your consent but are needed to be able to provide you the services that you'd like to use. We strongly recommend you to check which data you want to share, but also want to point out that certain services won't be able to be delivered fully or partly if you choose to not share certain information.

If you choose to give additional information about yourself, you explicitly give us permission to use that information as described in this Privacy Statement.

## What do we do with your personal data?

We use your personal data to:

  * Publish the information intended to be made public by you, under the conditions specified in your settings.
  * Allow you to correctly use the Website in accordance with your settings.
  * Perform general customer administration.
  * Improve search results.
  * Bring you in contact with sellers of houses, real estate agents and developers.
  * Send you communications about the Website, as well as our other products and services.
  * Provide you with advertisements tailored to your profile, based on your profile that we generate based on the data you share with us.
  * Able to provide our services as described on the Website (for example when requesting an estimate).
  * Investigate fraud.
  * Generate anonymous statistics about the (users of the) Website, to improve the Website or convey statistical information to third parties.
  * Register you with and display your profile on other social websites owned by Realo NV or its sister, daughter or parent companies.
  * Send your relevant details to real estate agents.
  * To answer on your question or your application for a job position to be evaluated

You may want us to send you emails with notifications about new messages or for other purposes related to the use of the Website. You can opt in or out from these messages in your "Settings".

## How your personal data is shared with third parties

Third parties can access all information intended to be made public by you, under the conditions specified in your privacy settings. Certain usage information can be accesses by trusted real estate agents and partners.

We hate spam as much as you do. Your email address is never shared by us with any third party, with the exception of sellers and trusted real estate agents or promoters.

Statistical or anonymous information about our users can be disclosed for marketing and promotional purposes. In these situations, we never disclose information that could be used to personally identify you.

We never share any of your other personal data with any third party, unless you give your explicit permission or in case of trusted partners such as real estate agents. We may, however, provide access to your personal data in case of illegal use, when we receive orders from authorized legal authorities or to protect our rights.

When we share data with partners that store data outside of the European Union (for example our helpdesk), then we'll make sure that these partners guarantee the application of an appropriate protection level, which allows the data to transfer to these countries.

For your convenience, we offer social login possibilities on the Website (i.e. Facebook Connect). We want to point out to you that if you opt to use this, that these login methods are susceptible to its own privacy policy and terms & conditions, drafted by the respective social media platforms. We recommend you to read up on these conditions before opting to use these functionalities.

## Cookies and web bugs

The Website uses cookies to identify you as a user of the Website, to remember your preferred language and to facilitate navigation on the Website. You can disable cookies in your Internet browser, although some parts of the Website will no longer function correctly if you do so. You can read our complete cookie policy here. 

## Storage term and location

Realo applies the following storage terms:

  * Information added you: stored during a period of 6 months after you delete this information, or delete your account or listing (Note: you can delete your account at any time. If you do not log in on your account during a period of 6 months, your account can be deleted automatically.) Information that you sent to use (i.e. question via helpdesk, answer on a job position, etc.) will not be stored longer than needed to handle your request. 
  * History and logs: stored during a period of 6 months after the history item or log event was created.
  * Cookies: cookies used on the Website have a maximum lifetime of 100 days.

## Security measures

The security measures put in place on Realo prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Realo uses industry standard efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information. While "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet, our technical experts at Realo work hard to ensure your online safety.

## Your rights

You can get access to your personal data free of charge (and restrict it, or have it corrected, where relevant). Please promptly update your information if it changes. This is possible in a number of ways: 

  * You can login into your account and edit all information you deem needed to edit via the 'Settings' section in the 'My Realo' tab.
  * You can also enter your address as a search query on the Realo homepage and be forwarded to the page of your home where all information is listed. You can click on 'More' and subsequently on 'Request of removal'.
  * You can contact us at all times via feedback@realo.com or via our [contact center](https://realo.zendesk.com/hc/nl/requests/new)

You can object to the use of your personal data for direct marketing purposes. 

Under the European privacy rules, people also have the right to transferability of their data. Since it's not clear yet in practice how this right will be applied, we gladly invite you to ask us questions related to this so we can search for a solution together. 

Although we prefer to come to a solution to all of your questions together, we inform you to your right to file a complaint with the Belgian Privacy Commission (https://www.privacycommission.be/). 

## Control of your password

You may not disclose your password to any third parties or share it with any third parties. Keeping your password safe is your responsibility.

If your password has been revealed or stolen, immediately change your password via Settings. Please inform us of any privacy breach or abuse of login data by sending an email to abuse@realo.com.

We strongly recommend that you periodically change your password. Choosing a safe password will reduce the risk of unauthorized access to your account.

## Changes to this Privacy Statement

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Statement will be posted on this Website so that you are always aware of the information that we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

Modified versions will take effect thirty (30) days after being published on the Website.
